Guide to the Williams Ampère collection, circa 1793-2005.
Williams, L. Pearce, Ampère Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Williams Ampère collection, circa 1988-2005.
4730
L. Pearce Williams, 1927-
18.5 cubic feet.
Manuscripts, printed material, publications, research material, photographs, microfilm
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Research materials on André-Marie Ampère compiled by L. Pearce Williams.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
History of science professor, Cornell University.
Cornell Class of 1949, Ph.D. 1952.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Research materials on André-Marie Ampère, including manuscripts and letters by Ampère, and manuscripts by contemporaries such as Etienne Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Jan Hendrik van Swinden, Justus Liebig, Charles Bonnet, Jean Senebier, and Maine de Biran. pThis collection consists of William's extensive notes in preparation for a book on Ampère. Includes photocopies of many items from other libraries; they remain in the collection perhaps to show items that Williams found important. Annotations by Williams are prevalent throughout. Order is not entirely clear, but folders may contain Williams's coding for organization. Williams had portions of his writing on Ampère published, but the monograph for which this work was prepared was not finished. Collection also includes microfilm of works by Ampère and his contemporaries.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Williams, L. Pearce (Leslie Pearce), 1927-; Ampère, André-Marie, 1775-1836.; Ampère, André-Marie, 1775-1836.; Geoffroy Saint-Hilaire, Etienne, 1772-1844.; Swinden, Jan Hendrik van, 1746-1823.; Bonnet, Charles, 1720-1793.; Senebier, Jean, 1742-1809.; Maine de Biran, Pierre, 1766-1824.
Subjects:
Electrodynamics.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Restrictions on Use:
Photocopies or other reproductions may not be quoted or reproduced without the permission of the repository holding the originals.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collection: L. Pearce Williams papers, #14-17-795.
CONTAINER LIST
- Lettre de Ampère à Berthollet (copies), 1815 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Considérations Générales sur les Intégrales des Équations aux Différentielles Partielles- Ampère, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bibliographies, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General Catalog/Location Information, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Démonstration de la relation découverte par Mariotte- Ampère, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Démonstration d'un théorème sur la double réfraction, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Essay par Ampère, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Démonstration de la relation découverte par Mariotte- Ampère, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- bibliotheque, re: Ampère, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Request for Ampère information from RLIN, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Classification des phénomènes physiologiques (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Misc. Notes and Records, 1936-45 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Latin Grammar (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Book Reviews- L. Pearce Williams (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Various Notes from Course in Hist 282 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Addt'l Books to get fro Olin Library- Cornell (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Misc. Notes/Articles mentioning Ampère (Box 1, Folder 17)
- French Language and Grammar Idioms (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Essai d'une Classification naturelle pour les Corps simples- Ampère, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- bibliotheque of Ampère's Publications (6+ copies) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Précis d'une Série d'expériences sur le Diamagnétisme- Oersted, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Programme du cours de Physique, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Manuscript on nature of electricity, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- De l'Action de la pile sur l'aiguille aimantée- Boisgiraud, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Journal de Physique de Chimie et D'Histoire Naturelle- Biot, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Misc. Mss., 1820 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Misc. Articles and Citations (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Naturphilosophie (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Journal de L'école Royale Polytechnique- Ampère, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Ampère mss. on electromagnetic actions, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Lettre de Ampère mss. à Erman, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Rapport fait à l'Académie des Sciences, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Expusé des découvertes, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Note sur un appareil à l'aide duquel on peut vérifier toutues les propriétés des conducteurs de l'électricité voltaique, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Mémoire sur quelques nouvelles expériences électro-magnétiques et en particulier sur celles de Faraday- Prof. De La Rive, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Conclusiones d'un Mémoire, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Rapport sur un ouvrage de Bremoutiér- Ampère, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Recueil- early copy, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Lettre d'Ampère à de la Rive, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Notes on Ampère's Physics class (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Recueil d'Observations Electro-dynamiques, 1822-23 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Précis d'un Mémoire sur L'Electro-dynamique- Ampère, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- File for research papers needing verification, found at Cornell, 1820-25 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Note sur les Expériences Electro-magnétiques de Ampère- Hachette, 1820-21 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mémoire sur Electro-magnétiques de Ampère- Hachette, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bibliographie de la France, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ampère for Acad. of Sciences Rapports, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Planche du Mémoire de Ampère, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Remarques sur un Rapport- Biot, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Supplément sur les recherche, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Notes by Ampère of the communications which he made to the Acad. of Sciences, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Considérations Générales sur les Intégrales- Ampère, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Suite de la Note sur un Appareil à l'aide duquel... -Ampère, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Lettre de Ampère à Aiago, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Biibliographie de la France, No.4 (peripheral), 1822 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Exposé Méthodique des Phénomènes Électro-dynamiques- Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Necrologie de Jordan(Camille), 1823 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Notes sur la Bibliographie de la France, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Annales de Mathématiques- Gerconne, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Notes sur la Bibliographie de la France, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Mémoire sur l'Action Mutuelle d'un Conduteur Voltcique et d'un Aimant, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Notes sur la Bibliographie de la France, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mémoire sur l'Action Mututelle d'un Conducteur Voltaique et d'un Aimant, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Llibreria Antiquària Comellas- Ampère, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Non-Ampère Letters (peripheral) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Notice sur Ampère (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Considérations- Avagadro (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Articel in Moniteur on Oersted, 1813 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Maine de Biran and Ampère (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Misc. non-notated articles and information (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Catalogue of Quetelet's Letters, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Kant on Religion (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Musée d'Ampère- Poleymieux (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Location of Ampère material at various libraries (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Important- Ampère's Experimental Proof, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Oersted's Latin Paper, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Oersted's Paper- translated into French, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Ancillary articles (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Misc. articles and research materials (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Mathesis- Theile; Steinle (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Mathematics in Germany and France in the early 19th century- Dauben (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Dibner Institute and Burndy Library: Ampère holdings (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Letter from Ampère to author of the Journal générale d'instruction ou education publique, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- découverte ou idées nouvelles de la tournée, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Misc. proofs (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Ampère- Rapport eur Binet (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Consultation with bureau on application for a patent- Bodmer (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Note...sur la propagation du son... follwed by rapport by Molut, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Mémoire sur les avantages qu'on peut retirer...- Ampère, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Bib. Mun. de Lyon, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Recherches- du calcul des variations (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Misc. research material (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Academy of the Sciences, Vol. 1; Receipt of Ampère's "math. du jeu", 1802 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Électro-dynamique, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- II. Sciences Physiques- Gay-Lussac et Thenard, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Correspondence: Ampère to Jussieu, 1811 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Mémoire contenant L'Application de la Théorie...- Ampère, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Correspondence- Liège to Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Exposé sommaire des nouvelles Expériences électro-magnetiques..., 1822 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire de Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Addition to Savary's account in Recueil, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Ampère as co-reporter, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- De l'Action qu'exerce...- De La Rive, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Historical sketch of electro-magnetism, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Recueil: Memories sur l'Action mutuelle...- annotations by Ampère to Faraday, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Experiences relatives à de nouveaux phénomènes électro-dynamiques- Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Notice sur de Nouvelles Recherches de Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Réponse de Ampère à la lettre de Van Beck, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Mémoire (sur la détermination de la formule qui represente l'action mutuelle...)- Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Ampère and Bureau de Consultation des Arts et Manufactures, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Research on Taylor Series, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Map of Paris (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Historical Sketch of Electromagnetism, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Mémoire (sur la détermination de la formule qui represente l'action mutuelle...)- Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Notice sur les expériences électro-magnetiques faites par différens Physiciens, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Lettre de van Beck and Réponse de Ampère, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Exposé Méthodique Des Phénomènes électro-dynamiques et lois de ces Phénomènes, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Correspondence- Ampère to de La Rive, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Rapport fait à l'Académie sur un Mémoire de Fresnel Fourier, Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire à l'Académie sur les Phénomènes électro-magnetiques- Pouillet, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Expériences relatives à de nouveaux phénomènes électro-dynamiques- Ampère, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Extrait d'une Lettre de Ampère au de La Rive, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Exposé des nouvelles découvertes sur l'Electricité et le Magnétisme, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Note sur un Mémoire lu à l'Académie royale des Sciences dans la séance- Ampère, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Chart of symptoms of mental activities (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Mémoire (sur quelques nouvelles propriétés des Axes...); Add'l note from 1823, 1821-22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Early Recueil- Various Sources, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Sur l'Application du Calcul aux Phénomènes électrodynamiques- Savary, Ampère, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Notes- Read at Académie on 12/22/1823, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Ampère on Recueil- Deutsches Museum, Paris, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Savary's Proofs corrected by Ampère, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Du Développement de l'électricité par le contact... - Becquerel, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Note- Bib. de la Ville de Lyon, 1823-24 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Académie- Rapport by Fourier, mentions of Ampère and Savary, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mémoire sure quelques nouvelles proprieter des Axes permanens de rotation des corps- Paris, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Annales de Chimie et de Physique- Gay-Lussac et Arago, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence- Ampère to A. de la Rive, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Eric Mendoza- Ampère's experimented proof of his law of induction, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Description d'un appareil électrodynamique construit par Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Correspondence- Faraday to Ampère, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Description d'un appareil électrodynamique construit- Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Précis de la Théorie des Phénomènes électrodynamiques- Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Recherches sur la détermination du système solide...-Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Note sur une Expérience relative à la nature du courant électrique- Ampère et Becquerel, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Précis de la Théorie des Phénomènes Électrodynamiques- Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Description d'un Appareil électrodynamique- Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Éxtrait d'un Mémoire sur la Théorie du magnétisme- Poisson, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Rapport sur un Mémoire de Rosseau- Ampère et Dulong, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire lu à l'Académie des Sciences- Savary, corrected by Ampère, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Précis de la Théorie des Phénomènes Électrodynamiques; et Description d'un appareil électrodynamique- Ampère, Crochard et Bachelier, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire sur les Phénomènes électrodynamiques, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Annales de Chimie et de Physique- Guy-Lussac et Arago, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire sur les Phénomènes électrodynamiques- Ampère, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Rapport sur un Mémoire de Rosseau- Ampère et Dulong, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Précis de la Théorie des Phénomènes électrodynamiques- Ampère, Crochard et Bachlier, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Note sur un fait communique a l'Académie (ans la séance de l'Académie)- Ampère et Becquerel, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Mémoire sur une nouvelle expérience électrodynamique- Paris (2 copies), 1825 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Du mémoire sur une nouvelle expérience électrodynamique, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Analogie entre les facultés numériques et les puissances, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Note sur une nouvelle expérience électrodynamique, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Exposition des principes du calcul des variations, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Correspondence from Ampère, 1831 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Duplicates- Mémoire ser un nouvelle expérience electro-dynamique, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Description d'un Appareil Électrodynamique- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Description d'un Appareil Électrodynamique, second edition- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Note sur un nouvelle expérience electro-dynamique- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Analise Transcendante, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Déviation de l'Aiguille aimantée par le courant d'une machine électrique ordinaire- Colladon, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Phénomènes Électrodynamiques- Guérin, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Note sur un nouvelle expérience electro-dynamique- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Mémoire (Sur quelques novelles propriétés des Axes permanens...)- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- (2 copies) Extrait d'un Rapport- Ampère, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Collection of previously published Mémoires, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Mémoire (sur la théorie mathématique des phénomènes électrodynamiques...), 1823-25 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Extrait d'un Mémoire sur les Phénomènes électrodynamiques, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Mémoire L'Application du calcul aux Phénomènes électrodynamiques- Savary, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Note sur quelques Phénomènes électromagnétiques, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Mémoire sur la Théorie du Magnétisme en mouvement- Poisson, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Manuscript of "Nouvelle expérience électrodynamique, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Théorie des Phénomènes Électrodynamiques- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Du Pouvoir cnducteur de l'Electricité dans les métaux... -M. Becquerel, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Précis d'un Mémoire sur L'Electro-dynamique- Ampère, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Sur les Relations qui existent entre les actions électriques et les actions chimiques -Sir Humphry Davy, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Annales de Chimie et de Physique- Poisson, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Note concernant les Phénomènes magnétiques auxquels le mouvement donne naussance- Arago, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Annales de Chimie et de Physique- Savary, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Analyse Transcendante- Ampère, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Mémoire sur l'action mutuelle d'un Conducteur Voltaique et d'un Aimant- Ampère, 1827 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Manuscripts, Charavay, 1824-25 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Proof Copy- Mémoire ser un nouvelle expérience électro-dynamique, 1825 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Cornell catalogue records for misc. Ampère articles, 1815 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Mémoire sur la Détermination de la surface courbe des ondes luminueses...-Ampère, 1828 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Note sur l'Action mutuelle d'un Aimant et d'un Conducteur voltaique- Ampère (Cornell's copy), 1828 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Note sur l'Action mutuelle d'un Aimant et d'un Conducteur voltaique- Ampère, 1828 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Annales de Mathématiques pures et appliqués- Ampère, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Astronomie- Démonstration élémentaire du principe de las gravitation universelle- Ampère, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Reports on Ampère's articles in Gergonne, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Solution d'un probleme de dynamique, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Annales de Mathématiques pures et Appliquées (Dynamique- sur la théorie des forces centrales)- Ampère, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Notes on heat, light, and vibratory motion, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Revue des Deux Mondes à Ampère, 1833 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Classification des Connaissances Humaines, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Ampère on thermo-magnetism, 1833 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Exhait d'une Lettre de Ampère a Faraday, 1823 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Note de Ampère sur une expérience de Pixii, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Note de Ampère sur une expérience de Pixii, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Annales de Chimie et de Physique- Guy-Lussac et Arago, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Note sur un Moyen de Guérison- Ampère et Martin Saint-Ange, 1834 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Demonstrations of refraction theorem, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Rapport de Ampère, 1833 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Ampère's theory of the Earth from Edinburgh New Philosophical Journal, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Théorie du calcul élémentaire, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Letter involving Williams' purchase of 'Théorie du calcul élémentaire', 1845 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Sur le mode de transmission des courants électriques et la théorie électro-chimique, par Ampère, 1849 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- The Discourse of Il Principe- Michael McCanles, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Annales de Chimie- Reponse, par J.A. Deluc, 1805 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Articles Acknowledging Ampère- Bochner, Woodruff, Gillispie, Siegfried, Hawkins, Seymour, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Bureau de Consultation (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Observations de M.Proust; Winterl; Oersted, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Bibliotheque from AC, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Ampère- Academy of Sciences Rapports (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Extrait d'une lettre de Ampère au Prof. De La Rive, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Essai de Statique Chimique- Berthollet, 1800 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz, Berlin, 1822 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Becky Hardie (Cornell)- copies of Ampère's Recueil (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Ampère's personal life (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Bibliographie de la France, 1811-32 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Revised- Essai sur la Philosophie des Sciences (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Location of list of Ampère Mémoires in S. de Physique- Vols. 91-95 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Records of locations of various Ampère mss. (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Cartons 34-36 non classe chants (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Addt'l lists of and notes regarding various Ampère works (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Ampère at Cornell (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Misc.- Notes and Photocopies (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Becky Hardie (Cornell)- Ampère's Recueil (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Cornell Recueil- Contents (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Extrait d'une lettre de Faraday à Hachette- reconnait Ampère (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Interesting Articles- Bibliographie de la France (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Mémoire sur la Réfraction de la Lumière- Ampère, 1815 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Duplicate article- Institut de France, published for Académie Royale des Sciences, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Cornell catalog location for Annales generales des sciences physiques, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Original- Journal de Physique de Chimie et D'Histoire Naturelle- Hachette, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Analyse des Mémoires lus par Ampère, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Note sur les expériences de Ampère, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Book Reviews- Isis, 63-219 p.562 Ampère, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Addt'l title locations- 'peripheral but worth looking at' (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Bulletin de la Société des Amis d'André-Marie Ampère, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Annales des Minse ou Recueil de Mémoires sur l'Exploitation des Mines, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Nouvelles Scientifiques- Physique Expériences électro-magnétiques, 1820 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Faraday und Liebig- Ein unbekannter Briefwechsel (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Misc. important documents (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Important Articles- Ampère and others, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Esquisse de l'oevre d'Ampère en chimie (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Des Actions électro-motrices produites par le contact des métaux et des liquides...- Becquerel, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Alzheimer file sources (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Biot et Couvier- Sur quelques propriétés de l'appareil galvanique, 1800 (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Rapport- pour Académie des Sciences, 1816 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Addt'l Articles- Quantum Field théorie, Big Bang théorie, Feynman diagrams (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Problème quadratique- Rapport, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Un Discours Inédit de A.M. Ampère (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Barruel- Teaching of Physics (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Essays by H. Davy (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Addt'l Ampère Letters (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Ampère on Committees- Rapport to Académie des Sciences, 1820s (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Précis de Calcul Différentiel et de Calcul Intégral (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Observations sur le Mémoire de Mr. Savary, 1823 (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Revue Encyclopedique- Bib. Univ. 17, pp. 16-20, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 79)
- Description d'un Appareil électro-dynamique- Ampère, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Cornell- bibliotheque (Box 4, Folder 81)
- Addt'l Bib. Information, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Abstract of the Report on Rosseau's Memoir- Ampère and Dulong, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 83)
- Journal Articles- Re: Ampère (secondary) (Box 4, Folder 84)
- bibliotheque- Ampère and others (peripheral) (Box 4, Folder 85)
- Addt'l citations and bibliographical information (various countries) of Ampère's work (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Bulletin Universel, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Extrait d'un Rapport fait à l'Académie par Ampère, 1825 (Box 4, Folder 88)
- Théorie des phénomènes électrodynamique, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 89)
- Nouvelle démonstration du principe des vitesses virtuelles- Ampère, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 90)
- Ampère sur géométrie- âge de treize ans, 1788 (Box 4, Folder 91)
- Cornell catalog search request- Ampère (Box 4, Folder 92)
- Histoire de L'Académie Royale des Sciences de L'Institut de France, partie physique, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 93)
- Correspondence- Ampère to Faraday, 1823 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Preface to Opere di A-M Ampère- Bertolini (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Works on Ampère- Kant (location: Paris) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Ampère- Maine de Biran (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Ampère's broken arm (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Small film documents- Bibliographie Ville de Lyon, 1808 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Chemistry and Philosophy (Theology) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Deboves-Delambre et Ampère, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Poleymieux au Mont-d'Or- Patrie d'Ampère (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Philosophy, Epistemology (Box 5, Folder 10)
- M. Durr, Ampère et la Chimie, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Musée d'Ampère- Poleymieux, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Related non-Ampère Material (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Mémoire sur son père (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Ampère's secondary chem. thesis (Box 5, Folder 15)